A Guide to the Edward H. Peeples Papers, 1988-2005
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Edward H. Peeples Papers, 1988-2005
The Library of Virginia
43965
4.05 cubic feet (9 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Edward H. Peeples, Richmond.
Biographical Information
Edward Harden Peeples was born on 20 April 1935 in Richmond, Virginia. He is the son of Edward Harden Peeples (1905-1986) and Lula Jane Stephens (1908-1986). Peeples earned his Bachelor of Science degree from Virginia Commonwealth University (1957), a Master of Arts degree from the University of Pennsylvania (1963), and a Ph.D. from the University of Kentucky (1972). He taught full-time at the Medical College of Virginia and part-time at the Richmond Professional Institute from 1963 to 1965. He is now Associate Professor Emeritus of Preventive Medicine at Virginia Commonwealth University, having served on the faculty there from 1968 to 1995.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1988-2005, of Edward H. Peeples (b. 1935) of Richmond, Virginia, containing his genealogical research on the Peebles/Peeples family of Charles City and Prince George Counties, and Richmond, Virginia, and North Carolina, South Carolina, and Scotland. There is also information on the allied families of Hill, Lawton, Simmons, Stephens, and Wood. The collection includes articles, bibliographies, brochures, clippings, correspondence, epitaphs, genealogical charts, family group sheets, and reports, histories, maps, military records, photographs, and information from published sources and websites. There is also a good deal of material on the South, including agriculture and rural life, the Civil War, homes and plantations, and slavery.
Contents List
- Addresses. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Agticulture and Rural Life. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Allendale on the Savannah by Alexania Easterling Lawton and Minnie Revves Wilson. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bonnicord and Other Prince George Estates. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Byrd - Westover. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Cedar Grove Cemetery (New Bern, NC). (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Cemeteries and Churches. (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
- Charts and Family Reports. (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
- Chronology/Timelines. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- The Church Hymnary. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Civil War. (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
- "The Civil War" by Ken Burns. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Compact Disc - Family Data Files. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Correspondence. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Daguerrotypes (Peeples/Woods). (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Eden, Vivia Peeples. (Box 2, Folder 7-9)
- Exhibits/Artifacts. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Family Books - Inscriptions. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Family History. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Family Notes. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Flowerdew Hundred. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Fort Mose by Jane Landers. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- The Last Foray by Chalmers Gaston Davidson. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Laughlin (Winnsboro, SC). (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Lawton. (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
- Military Service. (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
- Miscellaneous - Virginia, South Carolina. (Box 3, Folder 10-13)
- Native Americans. (Box 3, Folder 14)
- New Bern, NC - Maps, Brochures, etc. (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Obituaries and Death Certificates. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Other Research Materials. (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
- Paternal Lineage. (Box 4, Folder 4-7)
- Peebles: Ante 1600-1962 by Anne Bradbury Peebles. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Peebles - Bibliographies. (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Peebles - Brunswick County, VA. (Box 4, Folder 10)
- "Peebles Family of North Carolina and Virginia..." by Edythe Whitley. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Peebles - Friends (Quakers) Materials. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Peebles - Miscellaneous. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Peebles - Poythress. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Peebles - Prince George County, VA. (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
- Peebles, Dr. Robert Stockton Johnston - MCV. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Peebles - Scotland. (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
- Peebles Street (Richmond, VA). (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Peeples, Benjamin Willingham. (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Peeples - Census - South Carolina. (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Peeples - Contemporary Families and Individuals. (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Peeples - History - Chronology. (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Peeples, Mattie. (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Peeples - Related Families. (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Peeples, Rev. Dr. Robert E. H. (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Peeples - Site Guide (SC, VA, NC). (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Peeples/Peebles - Sources - Vol. I. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Peeples/Peebles - Sources - Vol. II. (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
- Peeples/Peebles - Sources - Vol. III. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Peeples/Peebles - Sources - Vol. IV. (Box 6, Folder 6-8)
- Peeples - South Carolina. (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Peeples - Virginia. (Box 6, Folder 10)
- "Pen and Ink Portraits: Short Sketches of Prominent Citizens of Hampton". (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Photographs. (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Pietrowski, Lois Peeples. (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Plantations, Houses, etc. (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
- Priester, Julia. (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Reunions. (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Search Resources. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- The Seekers: Pioneer Families of Nokomis and Laurel by Paul H. Turner and Joan Berry Turner. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Simmons Family Reunions - Guest Register, 1956-1980. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Slaves/Slavery. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Slavery - Background - No. 1. (Box 7, Folder 5-9)
- Slavery - Background - No. 2. (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
- Slavery - Background - No. 2. (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
- Slavery - Overviews. (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
- Slavery - South Carolina. (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
- South Carolina - County Info. (Box 8, Folder 7)
- South Carolina - County Info. - Aiken. (Box 8, Folder 8)
- South Carolina - County Info. - Allendale. (Box 8, Folder 9)
- South Carolina - County Info. - Barnwell. (Box 8, Folder 10)
- South Carolina - County Info. - Beaufort. (Box 8, Folder 11)
- South Carolina - County Info. - Charleston. (Box 8, Folder 12)
- South Carolina - County Info. - Hampton. (Box 8, Folder 13)
- South Carolina - County Info. - Jasper. (Box 8, Folder 14)
- South Carolina Low Country Trip, June 2001. (Box 8, Folder 15)
- South Carolina Low Country Trip, June 2001 (Flashdrive). (Box 8, Folder 16)
- South Carolina - Maps. (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
- South Carolina - Maps (Oversize). (Map-case 2, Drawer 11)
- South Carolina - Sources. (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Stephens. (Box 9, Folder 6)
- "Stephens Ancestors and Pioneer Relatives" by Clyde S. Stephens. (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Stephens - Charts and Family Reports. (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Stephens - Family Sites - Maps. (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Taylor, Tonya A. - Questions. (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Two Centuries of Lawtonville Baptists, 1775-1975 by Coy K. Johnston. (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Virginia County Formation. (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Wood-Hill. (Box 9, Folder 13-14)
- Wood-Peeples-Hill-Harper. (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Wood - Sources. (Box 9, Folder 16)